http://www.sfhumanesociety.com/privacynotice

File Lost Report
HomeAdoptAdoptable AnimalsDogsCatsSmall AnimalsParoled PupsCurbside AdoptionAdoption ProcessPreparing to AdoptApply To AdoptAdoption FAQAdoption Category DefinitionsServicesUnderdogs to SuperherosOther Adoption OrganizationsGeneral FAQWays to HelpGive NowDonateWish ListShopMatching Gifts ProgramCorporate GivingCorporate SponsorshipDonor ProgramsKennel SponsorshipsMemorial DonationsBecome a SFAHS MemberPlanned GivingAnnual EventsPaws to CelebrateCruisin' for CrittersKiddie CarnivalArtisans for AnimalsBark in the ParkThe Fur BowlCraft & Bake SalesPawliday Pet PortraitsFundraise For SFAHSCommunity FundraisersEvent RequestDoggie Bag Dine OutVolunteer OpportunitiesVolunteerBecome a VolunteerVolunteer FAQCommunity ServiceSenior ProjectsDIY ProjectsFosterBecome a FosterFoster Emergency ContactsFoster FAQYouth VolunteeringJunior VolunteerKids ClubService GroupAbout Service GroupsService Group FAQPet Owner ResourcesCaring For Your PetPet Food BankPet-Friendly HousingRe-Home Your PetMicrochippingVeterinarians & BoardingHelplinePet Behavior TipsVeterinary InformationWildlife InformationLost and FoundMissing a PetFound A PetFile A Lost Pet ReportServicesHumane Law EnforcementAfter-Hours Receiving AreaCommunityCommunity FundraisersDog-Friendly BusinessesCompanies That CareDoggie Bag Dine OutShopAboutAboutMission and ValuesOur HistoryLeadership TeamBoard of DirectorsVisit SFAHSToursSchool VisitsHours & LocationAdoption Center Visitation PolicyCareersJoin Our TeamOpen PositionsNews & EventsPress RoomUpcoming EventsMedia ResourcesEvent RequestContactContact UsDonateFrequently Asked QuestionsReport Animal Cruelty
HomeAdoptAdoptable AnimalsDogsCatsSmall AnimalsParoled PupsCurbside AdoptionAdoption ProcessPreparing to AdoptApply To AdoptAdoption FAQAdoption Category DefinitionsServicesUnderdogs to SuperherosOther Adoption OrganizationsGeneral FAQWays to HelpGive NowDonateWish ListShopMatching Gifts ProgramCorporate GivingCorporate SponsorshipDonor ProgramsKennel SponsorshipsMemorial DonationsBecome a SFAHS MemberPlanned GivingWills and Living Trusts Beneficiary DesignationsPet Guardianship ProgramAnnual EventsPaws to CelebrateCruisin' for CrittersKiddie CarnivalArtisans for AnimalsBark in the ParkThe Fur BowlCraft & Bake SalesPawliday Pet PortraitsFundraise For SFAHSCommunity FundraisersEvent RequestDoggie Bag Dine OutVolunteer OpportunitiesVolunteerBecome a VolunteerVolunteer FAQCommunity ServiceSenior ProjectsDIY ProjectsFosterBecome a FosterFoster Emergency ContactsFoster FAQYouth VolunteeringJunior VolunteerKids ClubService GroupAbout Service GroupsService Group FAQPet Owner ResourcesCaring For Your PetPet Food BankPet-Friendly HousingRe-Home Your PetMicrochippingVeterinarians & BoardingHelplinePet Behavior TipsVeterinary InformationWildlife InformationLost and FoundMissing a PetFound A PetFile A Lost Pet ReportServicesHumane Law EnforcementAfter-Hours Receiving AreaCommunityCommunity FundraisersDog-Friendly BusinessesCompanies That CareDoggie Bag Dine OutShopAboutAboutMission and ValuesOur HistoryLeadership TeamBoard of DirectorsVisit SFAHSToursSchool VisitsHours & LocationAdoption Center Visitation PolicyCareersJoin Our TeamOpen PositionsNews & EventsPress RoomUpcoming EventsMedia ResourcesEvent RequestContactContact UsDonateFrequently Asked QuestionsReport Animal Cruelty
Contact Us
Donate
Hours of Operation
Careers
File Lost Report
HomeAdoptAdoptable AnimalsDogsCatsSmall AnimalsParoled PupsCurbside AdoptionAdoption ProcessPreparing to AdoptApply To AdoptAdoption FAQAdoption Category DefinitionsServicesUnderdogs to SuperherosOther Adoption OrganizationsGeneral FAQWays to HelpGive NowDonateWish ListShopMatching Gifts ProgramCorporate GivingCorporate SponsorshipDonor ProgramsKennel SponsorshipsMemorial DonationsBecome a SFAHS MemberPlanned GivingWills and Living Trusts Beneficiary DesignationsPet Guardianship ProgramAnnual EventsPaws to CelebrateCruisin' for CrittersKiddie CarnivalArtisans for AnimalsBark in the ParkThe Fur BowlCraft & Bake SalesPawliday Pet PortraitsFundraise For SFAHSCommunity FundraisersEvent RequestDoggie Bag Dine OutVolunteer OpportunitiesVolunteerBecome a VolunteerVolunteer FAQCommunity ServiceSenior ProjectsDIY ProjectsFosterBecome a FosterFoster Emergency ContactsFoster FAQYouth VolunteeringJunior VolunteerKids ClubService GroupAbout Service GroupsService Group FAQPet Owner ResourcesCaring For Your PetPet Food BankPet-Friendly HousingRe-Home Your PetMicrochippingVeterinarians & BoardingHelplinePet Behavior TipsVeterinary InformationWildlife InformationLost and FoundMissing a PetFound A PetFile A Lost Pet ReportServicesHumane Law EnforcementAfter-Hours Receiving AreaCommunityCommunity FundraisersDog-Friendly BusinessesCompanies That CareDoggie Bag Dine OutShopAboutAboutMission and ValuesOur HistoryLeadership TeamBoard of DirectorsVisit SFAHSToursSchool VisitsHours & LocationAdoption Center Visitation PolicyCareersJoin Our TeamOpen PositionsNews & EventsPress RoomUpcoming EventsMedia ResourcesEvent RequestContactContact UsDonateFrequently Asked QuestionsReport Animal Cruelty
Privacy Policy
Home > Privacy Policy
Donor Privacy Policy We will not sell or trade our donors' names or personal information with any other entity, nor send mailings to our donors on behalf of other organizations. This policy applies to all information received by SFAHS, both online and offline, as well as any electronic, written, or oral communications. To the extent any donations are processed through a third-party service provider, our donors’ information will only be used for purposes necessary to process the donation.Privacy Notice  Sioux Falls Area Humane Society has created this Privacy Notice to explain what information we collect and how we will protect that information. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for our website: www.sfhumanesociety.com. In order to fully understand your rights, read this Privacy Notice and our Terms of Use. Sioux Falls Area Humane Society reserves the right at any time and without advance notice to change this Privacy Notice by posting such a revised Privacy Notice on our Site. Change to the Privacy Notice will be immediately effective unless otherwise specified. For significant changes, we may notify you by a pop-up window, a message on the website or through other means on the website.  If you have questions about this Privacy Notice or you want to exercise any rights it provides, contact the executive director at 605-338-4441, 3720 East Benson Road, Sioux Falls, SD 57104, or emailing frontoffice@sfhumanesociety.com with ATTN: Executive Director.What Information We Collect and How We Use That Information:  Our registration forms and donation forms require users to provide us with identifiable information (information from which your identity can be determined). This information may include but is not limited to your name, e-mail address, physical address, interests, and similar information. You may also request that we delete your online accounts (also referred to as the right to be forgotten) by contacting the executive director at 605-338-4441, 3720 East Benson Road, Sioux Falls, SD 57104, or emailing frontoffice@sfhumanesociety.com with ATTN: Executive Director. We do not request or store sensitive information (also known as special categories), such as credit card, social security numbers, race, country of origin and similar information. The Sioux Falls Area Humane Society does not sell or trade personal information (including email addresses) we collect.   We maintain your personal information only until the later of (1) the time needed to provide the information, product or service for which you provided it and (2) to comply with applicable law (such as tax and donation reporting).  We are located in South Dakota in the United States of America. All data we collect is provided to us within the U.S. and remains within the U.S. for the duration of our maintaining the information.  Internet Protocol (IP) Address:  We collect an IP address from all visitors to our website. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users’ movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized personalized content. IP addresses are sometimes considered personally identifiable information and accordingly, we keep them private and secure as the rest of the personal information we maintain.  Use of “Cookies” and Responses to Do Not Track Signals:  Our website may use cookies to enhance your experience. Cookies are pieces of information some Web sites transfer to your computer that is used for record-keeping purposes at many Web sites. Use of cookies makes Web-surfing easier by performing functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular Web site and to make sure you don’t see the same ad repeatedly. You do not need to permit the use of cookies to visit or use our website. However, if you do not allow cookies to be used, you may not have the same or as good of an experience as you would if cookies were permitted. You can check or change your cookie preferences by viewing the preferences or settings in your Internet browser. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show Sioux Falls Area Humane Society ads on sites (and sites to which they provide services) on the Internet. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies and other similar technology to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to our website.  You may opt-out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page https://support.google.com/ads/. You can also opt-out of some third-party vendors’ use of cookies by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page http://optout.networkadvertising.org.  At this time, we do not respond to do not track and similar requests or signals. See the “Do I Have Control Over How My Information Is Used?” and “Individual Rights” sections on this page for additional information on how you can change when we maintain your information and how it is used.
Do I Have Control Over How My Information Is Used? Information used for communication. You may opt-out of receiving communications from us by unsubscribing or sending an email to us at frontoffice@sfhumanesociety.com stating you want to opt-out of communications and include your email address.  Each of our communications (other than those that act as a receipt for registering for an event or making a donation) contains an unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email.  Information used for other purposes.We use your information only for the reason for which it was provided, to maintain your profile and other legitimate purposes (such as maintaining a confidential list of donors, tax and governmental reporting and accreditation purposes). At any time, you can contact the executive director at 605-338-4441, 3720 East Benson Road, Sioux Falls, SD 57104, or emailing frontoffice@sfhumanesociety.com with ATTN: Executive Director and we will delete your personal information unless we are required to maintain a copy for legal reasons. Opt-In We utilize an opt-in system for our updates and promotional communications. If you no longer wish to receive our updates and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each communication or by contacting us at frontoffice@sfhumanesociety.com.
Individual Rights In some jurisdictions (such as the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) individuals have individual rights regarding their data. In addition to the rest of this Privacy Notice, individuals whose live in these jurisdictions have rights that include (1) being informed about your data, (2) viewing and obtaining a copy of your data that we maintain, (3) amending your data, (4) the right to have your data erased (the right to be forgotten), (5) restricting our use of your data, (6) having your data ported (transferred) to another entity, (7) objecting to our use of your data, (8) the right to object to automated decision making, and filing a complaint with the appropriate governmental entity.  In other sections of this Privacy Notice, we have explained (1) how we use your data, (2) that you can ask to have your data removed by contacting us and (3) to restrict how we use your data or if you want to object to our further use of your data you can contact us. We do not make automated decisions about you.
Security All information provided to Sioux Falls Area Humane Society is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt or scramble data before you send it to us. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our website only accessible by certain employees with a need to know or access that information. Unfortunately, no data transmission method is 100% secure.  We strive to protect your information, but cannot ensure or warrant its security.   Our Site contains links to other Web sites that have their own privacy notices, terms of use and conditions of service.  We do not have control over, review or endorse these policies. Before clinking on these links, you should read these policies.  If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, the practices of this website, or your interaction with this website, you can contact the executive director at 605-338-4441, 3720 East Benson Road, Sioux Falls, SD 57104, or emailing frontoffice@sfhumanesociety.com with ATTN: Executive Director.
Why is an email address required to make an online donation? An email address is required to make an online donation because that is how we provide you with a receipt (including tax information).  You will receive news and marking material emails only if you have selected to check the box for those communications, otherwise known as “opt-in”. For those already receiving communications, you can opt-out of future correspondence by contacting the executive director at 605-338-4441, 3720 East Benson Road, Sioux Falls, SD 57104, or emailing frontoffice@sfhumanesociety.com with ATTN: Executive Director.
PCI-DSS Compliant Online donations and other financial transactions are completed through GreaterGiving powered pages on our website are PCI-DSS compliant. PCI-DSS is the payment card industry security requirement for entities that store, process or transmit cardholder data and has been endorsed by all the major card brands. PCI-DSS compliance gives consumers additional confidence by knowing that organizations accepting electronic payments or donations are doing so in a verified, secure, and consistent fashion. GreaterGiving, our software provider for online fundraising received Level 1 PCI compliance, the highest level validation. This means that the processes, procedures, network configuration and overall environment used to process your financial support of the Sioux Falls Area Humane Society met the stringent guidelines of a third-party audit and are in compliance with the standards set by the industry. This comprehensive standard is intended to help organizations such as ours proactively protect your account data, a responsibility we take very seriously. Tax DeductionThe Sioux Falls Aera Humane Society is a registered 501(c)(3) non-profit organization. Financial contributions are tax-deductible to the extent allowable by the law.
Copyright Notice © 2019. The Sioux Falls Area Humane Society (SFAHS).  All Rights Reserved. Last Revised: October 16, 2019
